<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>news summarizer on Thomas Lazarus</title>
    <link>https://lazarust.github.io/tags/news-summarizer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in news summarizer on Thomas Lazarus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://lazarust.github.io/tags/news-summarizer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>News Article Summarizer</title>
      <link>https://lazarust.github.io/post/news_text_summarization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lazarust.github.io/post/news_text_summarization/</guid>
      <description>News Text Summarization The Project The Idea The basic premise for this project was for my Capstone to get my B.S. in Computer Science. I wanted to create a site that would show summarized news articles since it there is so much and lot of people don&amp;rsquo;t have to the time to read them all. The proof of concept Jupyter Notebook can be found here.
Current News Sites These are the current sites that are scraped and summarized:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstractive News Summarizer</title>
      <link>https://lazarust.github.io/post/news_abstractive_summarization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lazarust.github.io/post/news_abstractive_summarization/</guid>
      <description>News Text Summarization It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve updated this site, but I&amp;rsquo;m considering this project as the end of my 100 days of code. This project was my capstone project for my senior year at Kansas State University and I was able to learn a lot from it. I hope that I will be able to continue to work on this project in the future and keep expanding it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> News Summaries</title>
      <link>https://lazarust.github.io/post/news_summaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lazarust.github.io/post/news_summaries/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this project is to learn about both abstractive and extractive text summarization using NLP and deep learning.
Extractive  This algorithim can be found in extractive.py. This algorithim works by ranking sentences based off importance and then compiles the top 50% of them.
Abstractive  Attempted to make an abstractive model to summarize the text. Ran into an issue encoding the text for the model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>